const quizDB = [
    {
        question: "Q1: REPL Stands For",
        a: 'Research Eval Program Learn',
        b: 'Read Event Print Loop',
        c: 'Read Earn Print Loop',
        d: 'Read Eval Print Loop',
        ans: "ans2"

    },
    {
        question: "Q2: Which of the following command will show version of Node?",
        a: "$npm --version",
        b: "$node --version",
        c: "$npm getVersion",
        d: "$node getVersion",
        ans: "ans2"
    },
    {
        question: "Q3: Which of the following statement is correct?",
        a: "js is Server Side Language.",
        b: "js is the Client Side Language.",
        c: "js is both Server Side and Client Side Language.",
        d: "None of the above.",
        ans : "ans1"
    },
    {
        question: "Q4: Which of the following command is used to start a REPL session?",
        a: "$ node",
        b: "$ node repl",
        c: "$ node start",
        d: "$ node console",
        ans : "ans1"
    },
    {
        question: "Q5: In which language is Node.js written?",
        a: "JavaScript",
        b: "C",
        c: "C++",
        d: "All of the above",
        ans : "ans4"
    },
    {
        question: "Q6: Which of the following command is used to install the Node.js express module?",
        a: "$ npm install express",
        b: "$ node install express",
        c: "$ install express",
        d: "None of the above",
        ans : "ans1"
    },
    {
        question: "Q7: Which of the following command is used to install the Node.js express module?",
        a: "$ npm install express",
        b: "$ node install express",
        c: "$ install express",
        d: "None of the above",
        ans : "ans1"
    },
    {
        question: "Q8:  Which of the following extension is used to save the Node.js files?",
        a: ".js",
        b: ".node",
        c: ".java",
        d: ".txt",
        ans : "ans1"
    },
    {
        question: "Q9:  Which of the following module is not a built-in node module?",
        a: "zlib",
        b: "https",
        c: "https",
        d: "fsread",
        ans : "ans4"
    },
    {
        question: "Q10:  Which of the following code print the platform of operating system?",
        a: "console.log('platform : ' + os.platform);",
        b: "console.log('platform : ' + os.platform());",
        c: "console.log('platform : ' + os.getPlatform());",
        d: "None of the above.",
        ans : "ans2"
    },
    {
        question: "Q11:  Which of the following method is used to return the current working directory of the process?",
        a: "cwd();",
        b: "dwd();",
        c: "pwd();",
        d: "None of the above.",
        ans : "ans1"
    },
    {
        question: "Q12:  Which of the following is not a valid language for Node.js?",
        a: "JavaScript",
        b: "C",
        c: "Java",
        d: "C++",
        ans : "ans3"
    },
    {
        question: "Q13:  Which of the following shortcut command is used to kill a process in Node.js?",
        a: "Ctrl + B",
        b: "Ctrl + K",
        c: "Ctrl + T",
        d: "Ctrl + C",
        ans : "ans4"
    },
    {
        question: "Q14:  How many Node object methods are available?",
        a: "21",
        b: "18",
        c: "19",
        d: "20",
        ans : "ans2"
    },
    {
        question: "Q15:  Which of the following route parameter formats are valid?",
        a: "/books/!:from-:to",
        b: "/flights/:from-:to",
        c: "/users/:userId/books/:bookId",
        d: "None of the above",
        ans : "ans1"
    },
    {
        question: "Q16: Which of the following module is required to create a web server?",
        a: "net module",
        b: "http module",
        c: "net module",
        d: "url module",
        ans : "ans1"
    },
    {
        question: "Q17: Which of the following is the correct syntax to initiate the Node.js File?",
        a: "filename.js",
        b: "javascript filename.js",
        c: "node filename.js",
        d: "node filename",
        ans : "ans3"
    },
    {
        question: "Q18: Which of the following platforms does Node.js support?",
        a: "Windows",
        b: "Macintosh",
        c: "Unix/Linux",
        d: "All of the above.",
        ans : "ans4"
    },
    {
        question: "Q19: Which of the following method can append specified content to a file?",
        a: "fs.appendFile()",
        b: "fs.open()",
        c: "fs.writeFile()",
        d: "None of the above.",
        ans : "ans1"
    },
    {
        question: "Q20: Which of the following areas, Node.js, is not advised to be used?",
        a: "Single Page Applications",
        b: "JSON APIs based Applications",
        c: "CPU intensive applications",
        d: "Data-Intensive Real-time Applications (DIRT)",
        ans : "ans3"
    },
]    